Mss.Rec.106 Mss.Rec.106
American Philosophical Society
Delaware Songs and Texts
1973-1974
Mss.Rec.106
American Philosophical Society
5.0 Tape(s)
4 sound cassettes (3 hr., 30 min.): analog, 1 7/8 ips, 1/4 track, stereo.
Performances of Delaware sacred and secular songs with interspersed commentary, commentary on Big House ceremony in Delaware in English, Delaware vocabulary, and prayers. Recorded by Sue Roark-Calnek in Oklahoma in Wann and Dewey, Oklahoma in 1973 and 1974.
Dean, Nora Thompson
Roark-Calnek, Sue N.
Washington, Fred
Wilson, Tom
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Presented by Sue Roark-Calnek in 1977. This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Big House Ceremony (Delaware rite); Delaware dance; Delaware Indians--Music; Delaware Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Delaware language; Ghost dance; Peyote songs; Prayers.; Sound recordings
- Delaware Sacred and Secular Songs: Fred Washington, 11-29-1973; Mss.Rec.106.1; 1.0 Tape(s)
  - Comments on Doll Dance Ceremony; Doll Dance Songs with comments, 1973-11-29; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:36; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Audiocassette) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Delaware dance; Delaware Indians--Music; Delaware Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Wann (Okla.)
  - Comments on Stomp Dance; Series of four Woman Dance Songs, 1973-11-29; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:37; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
    Delaware dance; Delaware Indians--Music; Delaware Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Stomp dance; Wann (Okla.)
  - Comments on Coon Dance; Series of Four Coon Dance Songs, 1973-11-29; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:59; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - Comments on Turkey Dance Songs; Two Turkey Dance Songs, 1973-11-29; 01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:41; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - Comments on Cherokee Dance Songs; Cherokee Dance Song, 1973-11-29; 01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:41; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
    Cherokee dance; Delaware Indians--Music; Delaware Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Wann (Okla.)
  - Comments on Ghost Dance; Ghost Dance Song, 1973-11-29; 01-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:27; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
    Delaware dance; Delaware Indians--Music; Delaware Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Ghost dance; Wann (Okla.)
  - Four Fish Moon "Starting" Songs; Comments on Fish Moon Peyotism, 1973-11-29; 01-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:18; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
    Delaware Indians--Music; Delaware Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Peyote songs; Wann (Okla.)
  - Comments on Midnight Water Songs; Midnight Water Songs, 1973-11-29; 01-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:44; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - Four Morning Water Songs; Comments on Ritual Meaning; Quitting Song, 1973-11-29; 01-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:48; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - Fish Moon Peyote Songs, and comments, 1973-11-29; 01-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:03; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - Fish Moon Peyote Song, 1973-11-29; 01-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:22; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - Fish Moon Peyote Song, 1973-11-29; 01-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:24; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - Fish Moon Peyote Song, 1973-11-29; 01-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:01; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - Fish Moon Peyote Song, 1973-11-29; 01-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:24; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - Fish Moon Peyote Song, 1973-11-29; 01-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:25; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - Comments on Big Moon ("Moonhead") Peyotism; Big Moon Starting Songs, 1973-11-29; 01-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:07; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - Big Moon Song, 1973-11-29; 01-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:31; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - Big Moon Song, learned from Charley White Horn (Osage), 1973-11-29; 01-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:43; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - Comments on Big House Ceremony; Ben Hill's Big House Vision Recitation Song, 1973-11-29; 01-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:35; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
    Big House Ceremony (Delaware rite); Delaware Indians--Music; Delaware Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Wann (Okla.)
  - Comments on Vision Recitation; Charley Elkhair's Big House Vision Recitation Song; Translation of song, 1973-11-29; 01-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:11; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - Frank Wilson's Song, with Translation, 1973-11-29; 01-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:54; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - George Washington's Vision and Song; Translation of Song; George Falleaf's Song, 1973-11-29; 01-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:10; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - Comments on Delaware War Dance; War Dance Song, 1973-11-29; 01-23; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:48; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - War Dance Song, 1973-11-29; 01-24; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:11; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - War Dance Song (fast), 1973-11-29; 01-25; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:59; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - War Dance (slow, "straight dance"), 1973-11-29; 01-26; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:38; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
- Delaware Big House Texts: Fred Washington, Mss.Rec.106.2; 1.0 Tape(s)
  - Narration (Delaware) on Big House Ceremony; Summary (English), 1973-11-29; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:19; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
    Big House Ceremony (Delaware rite); Delaware Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Wann (Okla.)
  - Comments (English) on Mesingw ("False Face") Spirit and Impersonation; Narration (Delaware) of Origin of Mesingw, 1973-11-29; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:31; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - Comments (English) on Big House Attendant Role and Ceremonial "Release" from Duty; Narration (Delaware) of Big House Speaker's Address to Attendants Releasing them from Duty, 1973-11-29; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:24; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
- Delaware Vocabulary: Fred Washington, Mss.Rec.106.3; 1.0 Tape(s)
  - Delaware Vocabulary: Fred Washington [1 of 2], 1974-06-24; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:54; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
    Scope and Contents note
    Consists of unelicited lexical items and expressions in Delaware with English gloss and some accompanying ethnographic information, mainly on plant use. The unordered lexical material consists primarily of substantives: terms for plants, animals, birds, weather phenomena, kin statuses, descent groups, ceremonial and secular dance regalia.
    Delaware language; Wann (Okla.)
  - Delaware Vocabulary: Fred Washington [2 of 2], 1974-06-24; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:36; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
- Delaware Prayer Texts: Nora Thompson Dean / Fred Washington, 12-16-1973; Mss.Rec.106.4; 1.0 Tape(s)
  - Prayer for Well-Being, 1973-12-16; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:00; Dean, Nora Thompson; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-
    Explanatory comments in English followed by a Christian prayer in Delaware.
    Delaware language; Dewey (Okla.); Prayers
  - Prayer for Well-Being, 1973-12-16; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:06; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
  - Prayer Appropriate for Invocation at a Performance, 1973-12-16; 04-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:13; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred
    Delaware Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Delaware language; Dewey (Okla.); Invocation; Prayers
- Delaware Sacred and Secular Songs: Fred Washington and Tom Wilson, 07-30-1974; Mss.Rec.106.5; 1.0 Tape(s)
  - Woman Dance Songs, 1974-07-30; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:38; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred; Wilson, Tom
    Delaware dance; Delaware Indians--Music; Wann (Okla.)
  - Coon Dance Songs; Comments on Coon Dance, 1974-07-30; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:19; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred; Wilson, Tom
  - Mesingw Dance and Mesingw impersonation in Big House; Mesingw Big House Song (sung on return of hunters), 1974-07-30; 05-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:49; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred; Wilson, Tom
  - Comments on Duck Dance; attempt to sing Duck Dance Song, 1974-07-30; 05-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:20; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred; Wilson, Tom
  - Cherokee Dance; Conversation on Cherokee Dance, 1974-07-30; 05-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:41; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred; Wilson, Tom
  - Delaware Flag Song, 1974-07-30; 05-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:56; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred; Wilson, Tom
  - Straight or Man Dance; Comments on Old Delaware War Dance; War Dance Song, 1974-07-30; 05-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:26; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred; Wilson, Tom
  - Series of Three 49 Dance Songs, 1974-07-30; 05-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:07; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred; Wilson, Tom
  - Snake Dance Song, 1974-07-30; 05-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:50; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Washington, Fred; Wilson, Tom